Are you looking for a free open-source
platform [music] to run AI agents on
autopilot? Let's discover Hermes Agent,
a self-improving agent runtime that
bundles persistent cross-session memory,
autonomous skill creation, and isolated
sub-agents for parallel work streams. It
allows you to schedule automations,
comes with tons of built-in tools,
supports any LLM provider, and ship with
native gateways for Telegram, Discord,
Slack, WhatsApp, and [music] more. All
from one process sharing the same
memory. To start using it, you can
self-deploy it on your device or server
by running these two commands on the
official website, or use a platform like
ours, Elestio, to deploy it seamlessly
on your server or the cloud provider of
your choice. We handle the installation,
backups, updates, and ongoing
maintenance for you. To start using
Hermes Agent on our platform, [music]
head to ls.io and click on login. Then
deploy my first service, search for
Hermes, select, choose between the
[music] different cloud providers,
regions, and service plans based on your
needs, and then click on next.
Change the service name, adjust more
advanced settings, and choose between
different level of support. The first
one is free and included by default.
Once you're all good, hit the create
service button.
Once the installation is finished and
your new Hermes instance is ready, you
will receive this email with the link to
access the UI, the agent monitoring
dashboard, but also instruction on how
to set up properly your instance.
Because on some software, we can't
configure everything right beforehand.
So now, what we need to do
is to look at these commands here. We
want to run them on our Hermes instance.
So go to Elestio on the dashboard of
your instance, go to tools,
and terminal. It will display the
instruction to access the terminal.
So, let's copy the password. Username
will be root, and we can follow the
link. Type root, paste the password, and
sign in. Okay, we are connected to the
terminal. Let's simply copy-paste these
commands. Here it is. Run.
And this command is to let us, as the
user, to choose the LLM provider we
want. So, you have many available, the
most famous one, such as Anthropic,
OpenAI, Google, Co-pilot, some less
well-known, and you can even connect
custom ones.
What I will use for this video is GitHub
Co-pilot. So, I will simply hit enter on
that, and I have different way to
connect to it. Either one, login with
GitHub, or enter a token manually. I
will choose one. I follow the URL and
follow the steps. I authorize it. The
connection between my Co-pilot account
and Hermes is successful. It lists me
the model available through my GitHub
Co-pilot subscription, and you can
choose the default model you want to
use.
Let's take Claude Opus.
Then, you can choose the reasoning
effort. So, be aware, the more you use
it, uh the more tokens it might use. So,
depending on what you are trying to
achieve, you can put more or less. I
will keep the default,
and I'm all good. If we read correctly
the instruction, then it tells us once
we have finished this to also run this
command. And also to not worry because
we can still configure things later, but
we will see it together. So, let's
simply paste the command. It's
restarting the Hermes agent and web UI,
and we are good. Let's start exploring
it. Let's go back to overview on our
instance. We have two URL we can use.
The first one is the admin UI that we
will use in this video mainly, and the
second one, which is more an agent
monitoring. We will explore both. Let's
start with the first one, copy the
password, and follow the link. Paste it
and sign in, and we arrive on a Hermes
UI.
So, let's quickly start to see if
everything is set up correctly just by
saying hello. And we are getting an
error. So, it seems that Cloud Opus 4.7
isn't working with Copilot. So, we can
try something else. Let's say 5.4 mini,
try it, hello, and it seems with GPT-5
mini it's working. So, so far we will
use this one. This is a classic chat
interface where you have all your
conversations, but with a few great
things. First, you can create AI
profile. So, here by default, we are on
the default one that is created
automatically. If we go to manage
profiles, we can have multiple ones. So,
if we click on the plus button, we are
able to name it and choose another LLM
for it. The profiles with Hermes is the
equivalent of agents. So, you can see
them as different persona, or to have
one uh specialized in specific skills
based on the LLM model you will use, the
resources you will allow them, allowing
you to create a real virtual team. Let's
say for content creation, you use of
these models, for marketing, you use
that, for coding, something else. You'll
find the perfect recipe for each use
case. If we go back to the chat, you can
also choose from which workspace you
work from. Because uh the different
agents work on your server, each agent
will have its own workspace, but you can
also use sub workspaces for specific
tasks and projects. As you've seen
earlier, you can define what model you
want to use per message, and here we
have only uh connected GitHub profile,
but as you can connect multiple
providers. And the list can be very
long. So you can choose it by message,
but also per profile. Here by default
this is the one you configured earlier,
but we will change it later. And more
than that, you can adjust the intensity
you want to use based on what you ask
the AI. And you also have details about
the context.
By default each chat session appear in
the all, but inside it you can create
sub projects. A very useful feature not
present in most of the public AI
providers. Let's say content
creation.
And of course, inside a project you also
have the liberty to choose between the
different um profiles you created. Let's
dive into what we can do. So you have
the chat where you can talk to your
agent, even if most of the time you will
talk with your agent using a messaging
gateway. So you can see most of the
providers. Most of the typical one are
available with Hermes. But what can make
them really unique is to create skills
to your agent. The skills can be defined
per agent, per profile, and you have a
lot that are available by default. For
example, creative architecture diagram.
You are able to see what it contains,
edit it, delete it, and also add new
ones. You can ask your AI to do things
directly in the chat, but also to
schedule tasks. So you would say every
morning at this time you would do that.
Every week you would do that procedure.
And it's a very easy to set up,
especially with this interface. So you
can name create something. For the
schedule, it's either a chronic
expression or you can write every 1
hour.
Prompt, create a random art.
And you can also attach a skill to it.
I've seen earlier you have an ASCII art
one, so let's select it.
Save it.
So, the job is created and we can try to
run it.
You can see the job is running, but I
think it will fail. So, if we open it,
we can see it failed and it's because
the default LLM for this profile is the
one that doesn't work. So, let's change
it. If we go to settings,
um default model here,
I don't remember which one we were using
GPT-5 mini. Let's keep this one, we know
it works.
Save settings. Another thing we can do
to organize the workload we want to give
to our agent is not with scheduled task,
but with the Kanban, so real project
management. Uh we won't use this UI
because for any reason the plus button
doesn't work here.
So, it's the right moment to switch to
other agent monitoring UI. So, copy the
password and go to it. You arrive on
this more modern user interface where
you can change the theme with the
different colors you like.
I don't understand exactly why they have
these two UI because some things work
here and don't in the other and some
don't work here that work in the other.
For example, you can chat directly here.
It's more for monitoring, but
the Kanban plugin only works here. So,
you can see you can add different tasks
in the to-do, for example,
new task title do X on Y project. You
assign someone
to bot. You choose the skill you want to
use.
You create it and once you're good with
all the different things, you can run
that dispatcher.
And if you don't want scheduled job and
you don't want to use a full project
management software, you can use even
more simple thing. And for this one, I
need to go to the old UI, which is the
task list. It looks a very similar to
Cloud Co-work, where you can give
instruction to your AI and it will run
it in a specific workspace. So, let's
keep home, but you can choose a
different one. Let's say generate a
random name generator. For this one,
we'll use Grok code fast. Enter. The AI
is working on it. We can see what it's
doing in real time. So, it's writing a
file,
a Python script. As we didn't give any
instruction about it,
it finished. It shows us the full code
that it generated and gave us also a
sample run. So, here it's a very simple
example, but know that it's running on a
dedicated server and you can give it
task and it will work on its own
isolated. If we go back to the
monitoring UI, you can have access to
analytics to see the different models
that you used and number of token used.
So, I think the best screen is here,
models.
And you have clear details about the
usage. You also have the other feature
we saw together in the other UI that you
can also set up here, but some are not
available. For example, you can't create
a skill unless I didn't find where from
here and you can't have access to the
detail. You can just enable disable them
from here. But again, most of the time
you won't use the UI unless for the
initial setup and you will talk directly
to your AI using your favorite platform,
such as Telegram, Discord, Slack,
anything else. As always, I highly
recommend you to dive into the
documentation for the different features
I didn't cover in this video that could
be useful for you to set up your AI
agents. Thank you for watching. We hope
you enjoyed discovering Hermes with us.
Please hit the like button to help our
channel be more visible [music] to other
open source lovers. Don't forget to
subscribe to not miss our next platform
[music] overviews. If you want to
continue your open source journey, watch
this video available here.